The battle began in another galaxy. It's about to end in the Brown's backyard.
Critters is a comedy, horror, science fiction film directed by Stephen Herek.
Carnivorous aliens arrive unannounced at a Kansas family farm; two intergalactic
bounty hunters soon follow, determined to blow them off the planet.
Helen Brown, played by Dee Wallace.
Harv, played by M. Emmet Walsh.
Jay Brown, played by Billy Green Bush.
Brad Brown, played by Scott Grimes.
April Brown, played by Nadine Van der Velde.
Charlie McFadden, played by Don Keith Opper.
Critters is a 1986 American science fiction comedy horror film directed by Stephen
Herek in his directorial debut, and co-written with Domonic Muir.
It stars Dee Wallace, M.
Emmet Walsh, Billy "Green" Bush and Scott Grimes in his film debut.
The plot follows a group of small, furry aliens with carnivorous behavior escaping from two
shape-shifting bounty hunters, landing in a small countryside town to feast on its inhabitants.
Although widely believed to have been inspired by the success of Joe Dante's 1984 film Gremlins, Herek has refuted this in interviews, pointing out that the script was
written by Muir long before Gremlins went into production and subsequently underwent rewrites to reduce the apparent similarities between the two films.
The film grossed $13.2 million during its release in the United States, and spawned a Critters franchise
consisting of three sequels and a web series titled Critters: A New Binge released on Shudder.
The fifth entry Critters Attack!
serves as a reboot of the series.
The film explores themes of spacecraft, small town,
sheriff, bounty hunter, sibling relationship.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and thought_provoking.